<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Dr. Amani Jambhekar MD, MBA</title>
    <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Dr. Amani Jambhekar MD, MBA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 22:27:21 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Future Surgeons Journal Club</title>
      <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/fsjc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/fsjc/</guid>
      <description>To encourage future surgeons to become comfortable reading new research, I started the Future Surgeons Journal Club. We host approximately monthly reviews of a single new or particularly groundbreaking piece of surgical literature on Instagram Live. Students from high school through medical school are invited to read the paper ahead of time, follow along as key figures and findings are discussed, and ask clarifying questions as they arise. Since its founding in May 2020, FSJC has been hosted by a variety of guest moderators who have been able to provide insights from their respective fields of expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Heroes Need Masks</title>
      <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/real-heroes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/real-heroes/</guid>
      <description>Through much of the COVID-19 pandemic, one of the key barriers to providing safe and effective care for all patients has been the lack of personal protective equipment (PPE) for healthcare workers. Real Heroes Need Masks started as a project for a Kelley School of Business weekend design sprint, but was one of the few projects that sustained itself long afterwards and created a real impact in the communities it touched.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virtual Mentor</title>
      <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/virtual-mentor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/virtual-mentor/</guid>
      <description>As someone vocal about the grueling and often confusing process of embarking on a career in healthcare, students frequently asked me questions to try to make more informed decisions along their own paths. I realized that I would have loved to have had the benefit of a rich resource of information from those already in the field. That is what drew me to create The Virtual Mentor, a website and community focused on building up such a resource for the generations of healthcare workers to come.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
