<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Dr. Amani Jambhekar MD, MBA</title>
    <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Dr. Amani Jambhekar MD, MBA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 22:27:21 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Future Surgeons Journal Club</title>
      <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/fsjc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/fsjc/</guid>
      <description>I started the Future Surgeons Journal Club to help future surgeons develop a skill set to critically analyze surgical literature; I simultaneously wanted to highlight female surgeons in various surgical subspecialities. We host monthly reviews of a landmark papers on Instagram Live. Students from high school through medical school are invited to read the paper ahead of time, follow along as key figures and findings are discussed, and ask clarifying questions as they arise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Heroes Need Masks</title>
      <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/real-heroes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/real-heroes/</guid>
      <description>During the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic, one of the key barriers to providing safe and effective care for all patients has been the lack of personal protective equipment (PPE) for healthcare workers. Real Heroes Need Masks started as a project for a Kelley School of Business design sprint and lasted until supply chains could ramp up mask production again.
My core realization was that overworked hospitals in underserved regions rarely had the extra administrative time to apply to receive masks or other PPE from larger mask supply initiatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virtual Mentor</title>
      <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/virtual-mentor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/virtual-mentor/</guid>
      <description>As someone vocal about the grueling and often confusing process of embarking on a career in healthcare, students frequently asked me questions to try to make more informed decisions along their own paths. I realized that I would have loved to have had the benefit of a rich resource of information from those already in the field. I subsequently created The Virtual Mentor, a website and community focused on building up such a resource for the generations of healthcare workers to come.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
