<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Amani Jambhekar MD, MBA</title>
    <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dr. Amani Jambhekar MD, MBA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 22:27:21 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanijambhekar.md/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 22:27:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanijambhekar.md/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m a Columbia-trained surgeon with an MBA from Kelley School of Business. I have been passionate about using my experience and training to advocate for the underprivileged and underrepresented wherever I can, and have found many opportunities and friends along the way.
I am innovating in the use of social media to educate people interested in learning and growing with me. Check out some of my projects and campaigns in the Projects section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Press</title>
      <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/press/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 22:27:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanijambhekar.md/press/</guid>
      <description>Some links to things people have said about me.
 Poets and Quants 2020 Best and Brightest Online MBA Hometown Heroes &amp;ndash; KRIV TV Interview Real Heroes Need Masks &amp;ndash; Indiana Daily Student Medelita Interview  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Background</title>
      <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 22:27:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanijambhekar.md/professional/</guid>
      <description>Surgery I am currently leading the breast surgical oncology program for Millenium Physicians, a multidisciplinary clinical group with offices around Greater Houston. Prior to joining Millenium, I completed my Breast Surgical Oncology fellowship at Columbia University Medical Center and my General Surgery residency at New York Presbyterian Brooklyn Methodist Hospital, both in New York City. I received my MD from University of Texas Health Science Center at San Antonio. During my undergraduate education I triple majored in English, Biology, and Psychology and received a BA and BS from Tulane University in New Orleans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Surgeons Journal Club</title>
      <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/fsjc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/fsjc/</guid>
      <description>To encourage future surgeons to become comfortable reading new research, I started the Future Surgeons Journal Club. We host approximately monthly reviews of a single new or particularly groundbreaking piece of surgical literature on Instagram Live. Students from high school through medical school are invited to read the paper ahead of time, follow along as key figures and findings are discussed, and ask clarifying questions as they arise. Since its founding in May 2020, FSJC has been hosted by a variety of guest moderators who have been able to provide insights from their respective fields of expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Heroes Need Masks</title>
      <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/real-heroes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/real-heroes/</guid>
      <description>Through much of the COVID-19 pandemic, one of the key barriers to providing safe and effective care for all patients has been the lack of personal protective equipment (PPE) for healthcare workers. Real Heroes Need Masks started as a project for a Kelley School of Business weekend design sprint, but was one of the few projects that sustained itself long afterwards and created a real impact in the communities it touched.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virtual Mentor</title>
      <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/virtual-mentor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanijambhekar.md/projects/virtual-mentor/</guid>
      <description>As someone vocal about the grueling and often confusing process of embarking on a career in healthcare, students frequently asked me questions to try to make more informed decisions along their own paths. I realized that I would have loved to have had the benefit of a rich resource of information from those already in the field. That is what drew me to create The Virtual Mentor, a website and community focused on building up such a resource for the generations of healthcare workers to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes, me - I can</title>
      <link>https://amanijambhekar.md/posts/yes-me-i-can/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 21:28:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanijambhekar.md/posts/yes-me-i-can/</guid>
      <description>All women are still haunted and fighting,
The invisible demons, trolls, and ghosts,
Shaming, victim blaming, and gaslighting,
We push through the struggle while being good hosts. Post the Me Too era but pre Yes, Me
Have we faced biases? I have, me too
Discrimination and he above she?
We keep marching for the dreams we pursue.
So when will the Yes, Me era arrive?
When the right answer can also be “her,”</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
